Guide to the Robert L. Patten academic papers, 1963-2015 MS 410
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Robert L. Patten academic papers
1963-2015
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Patten, Robert L.
MS 410
103.5 Linear Feet (117 boxes)
Course materials, notes, correspondence and administrative papers of Dr. Robert L. Patten, Lynette S. Autrey Professor in Humanities at Rice University, Houston, Texas. Dr. Patten's research areas include Nineteenth-century British literature and art, and history of the book.
Biographical Sketch
Robert L. Patten, the Lynette S. Autrey Professor of Humanities at Rice University, was born on April 26, 1939 in Oklahoma City. He received his B.A. from Swarthmore College in 1960. He went on to earn an M.A. (1962) and Ph.D. (1965) from Princeton University. After college, Patten lectured in English at Bryn Mawr College, leaving there in 1969 to take a position as Assistant Professor in the English Department at Rice University, where he became a full professor in 1976. In 1991 and 1992 Patten chaired Rice's English Department.
Robert L. Patten was a Fulbright Scholar from 1963 to 1964 and a Guggenheim Fellow in 1980. He was also chosen as a Couper Scholar in 2004, served as president of the Rice University Chapter of Phi Beta Kappa from 1991 to 1994 and 1997 to 2002, and chaired the Dickens Society in 1973 and 1974. Patten has served in numerous capacities at Rice University, including the Sallyport Award Committee (1986-87), the Advisory Committee on Parking (1992-94), and the University Review Board (1982-84). He currently is president of the Society for the History of Authorship, Reading, and Publishing. In addition to the definitive biography, George Cruikshank's Life, Times, and Art (1991, 1992 ), Patten is the author of Charles Dickens and His Publishers (1978), and editor of George Cruikshank: A Revaluation (1974) and Literature in the Marketplace: Nineteenth-Century British Publishing and Reading Practices (1995). He also serves as editor of Studies in English Literature and founded and briefly edited the periodical Dickens Studies Newsletter.
Scope and Contents
Course materials, notes, correspondence and administrative papers of Dr. Robert L. Patten, Lynette S. Autrey Professor in Humanities at Rice University, Houston, Texas. Also included is material, correspondence, chapter material and notes relating to the publication, Palgrave Advances in Charles Dickens Studies (2006), edited by Robert L. Patten. Papers, correspondence and notes regarding Rice University, English Department business are part of the collection.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research with the exception of these restricted materials: box 11, folders 4-8; correspondence, classes, student papers, and Rice-related boxes 12-81; Phi Beta Kappa materials box 87, folder 7 through box 89, folder 6; oversize box 111. Please see Woodson Research Center Director for information on access.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Provenance
Materials were donated in 1999 with accruals added.
Related Materials
See Robert L. Patten: George Cruikshank research materials, MS 493, Woodson Research Center
See George Cruikshank letters, 1845, 1868, MS 297, Woodson Research Center
Index Terms
Subjects
Literature; Universities and colleges
Document Types
reports; lecture notes; corrrespondence; theses; essays
Subjects (Persons)
Patten, Robert L.; Patten, Robert L.
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University. Department of English; Swarthmore College
- Series I: General Academic Files, 1963-2005, Includes files relating to Robert L. Patten's involvement in professional associations and committees (Rice University and others), correspondence, lectures, early writings, student advising and other professional and academic activities.
  - Plot in Charles Dickens' Early Novels, 1836-1841, [thesis], 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to Mrs. Tillotson regarding Oliver Twist, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dickens Fellowship Dinner, 1965, February 12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dissertation, Plot Development in Dickens' Novels, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Plot Development in Dickens' Novels, bibliography, notes, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Thesis chapter, "Point of View," 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation, chapter one, "Plot in Prose Fiction," circa 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lecture illustration (text), The Old Curiosity Shop, Barnaby Rudge, circa 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, fellowships, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Rice University, English Department Graduate Committee, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Employment, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Society of Learned Societies, fellowship, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Modern Language Association, Dickens Seminar, 1969 December (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Modern Language Association, Dickens Seminar, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - English graduate brochure, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - London Centenary Celebration, 1970 June (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Graduate English Committee, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Institute of Banking, public speaking contest, 1971 May (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Richardson College, freshman advising, 1971 Fall (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Brown-Richardson Colleges, Cultural Awareness course, 1971 Fall (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - SCMLA, "Pickwick's Picaresque Pilgrimage," 1971 October (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Dickens Society, annual meeting, 1971 December (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - English Department, notices, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, correspondence, planning, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Flyleaf, correspondence, 1972 February (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Victorian Society in America, annual meeting, 1972 March (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Richardson College Night, 1972 August (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - American Philosophical Society, grant application, 1972 August (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - English Department, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - The Dickens Society, correspondence and meeting materials, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Philosophical Society, grants, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Dickens edition and concordance correspondence, 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - English Department, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Carroll Camden remarks, 1974 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Princeton graduate almuni in English, 1974 June (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, Houston site visit, 1974 December (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - The Dickens Society, meeting materials, 1974 December (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Rice Univeristy notices, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Fellowhships, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 19th Century books, C.C. Kohler correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - International Association of Business Communications correspndence, 1975 May-June (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Public Goals and Expectations of Health Care seminar, 1975 December (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - St. Mark's adult group, "A Dickensian Christmas," 1975 December (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Friends of Fondren Library, Christmas presentation, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - English Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Dickens Society correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Ashton Villa Lecture Series, number 1, "External Form, Interior Vision: Background in Art and 19th Century Culture," 1976 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Ashton Villa Lecture Series, number 2, "Dear Reader," 1976 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "Charles Dickens as Literary Croesus," Baker Associates Night, 1976 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Child Care seminar, 1976 April 24 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - English Institute, 1976 Fall (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Theology and Literature for Institute of Religion," 1976 October 5 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Value of Life Project, Texas Conference of Churches, 1976 December (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Charles Dickens and his American Publishers," Dickens Society Annual Meeting, 1976 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - English Department, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Society of Rice Univeristy Women, "What the Dickens?" 1977 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Institute, 1977 March (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dickens Studies Annual, Robert L. Patten, editor, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Houston, 2001: A Livable City, "Reading the City," 1977 November 12 and "Interim Perspectives," 1977 November 11 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Rowlandson Symposium, Yale Center for British Art, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, fellowship materials, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Houston Center for the Humanities, reports and meeting materials, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Alumni Institute, 1978 Fall (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Victorian Society in America, Dickens on the Strand, 1978 December 9 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Houston Post, Dickens article, 1978 December 17 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - English Department, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Baker College Associates, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Dickens Time and Again," circa 1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, correspondence, 1979 April-May (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - St. John's College, Annapolis and Santa Fe, presidency search materials, 1979 April-June (Box 2)
  - English Department, Graduate Studies, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Texas Committee for the Humanities, meeting materials, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - New York Review of Books, 1980 March (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Texans for Libraries, correspondence and articles of incorporation, 1980 March (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Alumni Institute, 1980 Spring (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Victorian English Luncheon, planning, 1980 December (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Dickens Society Dinner, 1980 December (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - U.S. Embassy (London) Speaker's Bureau, correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Dickens Society, correspondence and organizational materials, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Miami University, European Center, Luxembourg, 1981 March 12 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - University of Leicester, Victorian Studies Centre, "George Cruikshank in the '50s," 1981 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Dickens conference and symposium, 1981 December (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Modern Language Association, annual convention, "Dickens in his Time-Ly-Less-Ness," 1981 December (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - New York University, Dean of Faculty of Arts and Science search, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Publication advice, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Dickens Society, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Baylor University, Victorian Conference, 1982 March (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Yale Center Symposium, 1982 April (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Victorian Popular Entertainment seminar materials, 1982 April (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - NEH grant, 1982 July-August (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Victorian Institute conference, "The Professional Author in Victorian England," 1982 October 9 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Victorians Institute conference, "Professionalization of Letters in 19th Century England," 1982 October (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Modern Language Association seminar correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - English Department, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Appointment related - correspondence and reports, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - The Dickens Companions, correspondence, newsletters, 1982-1983, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "A Tribute to Vassar Miller," University of Houston, 1983 October (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - University of Southern California, publishing correspondence, 1983 October (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Berry College, " 'Their Own Myths': Charles Dickens, George Cruikshank, and Oliver Twist," 1983 Fall (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Oxford University Society of Bibliophiles, 1983 Fall (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Graduate status, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - English Department, Undergraduate Committee, 1983-1984, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Graduate registration, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Culture of Capitalism program, "Dickens, Scrooge and Reaganonimcs," 1984 Fall (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ohio State University position, 1984 Fall (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Graduate students report, 1984 November (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Dickens on the Strand, costume judging, 1984 December (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - English Department, Graduate Committee, admissions and financial aid, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - City University of New York, Lehman College Provost search, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - PEN Southwest, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Dickens Project, Santa Cruz, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Modern Language Association, 1985 January (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - LSU Autobiography Symposium, "Etched on Glass, Writ on Water: George Cruikshank's Autobiography," 1985 March (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Southern Graphics Council, "When Artists Saved the State: Graphic Satire in Georgian England," 1985 March (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Rice University Symposium on "Metaphors and Symbols of Discourse about Health, Illness, and Medicine, Is There a Doctor in the House of Fiction," Spring 1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - CUNY Victorians Conference, "George's Hive and the Georgian Hinge," 1985 May (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cultural Arts Council, minutes, 1985 October (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Dickens Theater, UT Austin, 1986 January - February (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Swann Foundation for Caricature and Cartoon, 1986 Spring (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - The Coherent Minor, 1986 December (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Modern Language Association Convention, interviews, 1986 December (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Brown College Associate, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Rhodes-Marshall scholarship interviews, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - English Department, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Mellon Summer Workshops, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Houston Center for the Humanities, 1987 October (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Victorian Institute, 1987 October (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Dickens class, Edwin S. Jenks, 5th grade, 1987 December (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Research programs/NEH, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center, director search, 1988 Spring (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Mississippi State University, 1988 October (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Center for Advanced Study in Visual Arts, "Diagrams of Drunkenness: George Cruikshank's Temperance Art," 1988 November (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - American Association of University Women, "Bah! Humbug! The Miser as Christmas Spirit," 1988 December (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Rice University Press, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - National Gallery of Art, fellowships, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Getty Foundation, 1989 February (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - English Department, 1989 Fall (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Washington Collegium for the Humanities, "Childhood in Crisis," 1989 October (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - English Book Illustration in a Eruopean Context, symposium, Berlin, 1989 December (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Modern Language Association, convention, "Dickens, Cruikshank, and the Death of the Author," 1989 December (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Paul Mellon Centre for Studies in British Art, conference, 1989 December (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - NEH research grants, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Rhodes-Marshall scholarships, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Charles Dickens and His Publishers, re-issue, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Moody Chair search, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - English Department, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Rhodes-Marshall scholarships, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - [Rice English Department] Symposium on Literary Criticism and Theory, "Dickens, Cruikshank, and the Death of the Author," 1990 February (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dickens Project, 1990 February (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Midwest Victorian Studies Association meeting, "Cruikshank's Margins," 1990 April (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Research Society for Victorian Periodicals, "The Artist as Editor: George Cruikshank's Periodicals," 1990 September (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - South Central Modern Language Association meeting, "Copyediting, Ethics, Asthetics, Politics," 1990 October (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dickens Project, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Grunwald Center for Graphic Arts, UCLS, director search, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hamilton College [NY], exhibition, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Illustrations for Sketches by by Boz, circa 1990 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Friends of Fondren Library, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Interdisciplinary 19th Century Studies conference, 1991 April (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Dickens Project, 1991 August (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - English Department, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - IRC Steering Committee, circa 1992 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Textual Technologies Text, Image, and History Conference, 1992 March (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Council of Editors of Learned Journals, contest, 1992 December (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center, list of holdings, 19th Century women writers, 1992 February (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Cruikshank exhibition at Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - NEH Dissertation grants program, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - English Department, meeting materials, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Dissertations directed, 1992-1993, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - English Graduate Committee reports, memos, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - N.I.C.E. meeting materials, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Dickens Society, correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 4)
  - Society for the History of Authorship, Reading and Publishing, conference, "Visual vs Verbal Literacy in the 1830's," 1993 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Friends of Fondren award, 1993 October (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Center for the History of the Book, inauguration, "When Is a Book Not a Book?," 1993 November (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Galveston College Lecture Series, "The Mystery of Charles Dickens," 1993 December (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Museum of Printing History, "Story Time" Project, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Dickens Project, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - South Central Society for 19th Century Studies, meeting, 1994 February (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - "Visualizing Aids," panel discussion, 1994 March (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Society for the History of Authorship, Reading and Publishing (SHARP), annual conference, "Oliver Twist's Contexts," 1994 July (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Center for Renaissance and Baroque Studies seminar, "Workshop: The Early Nineteenth-Century Urban Sketch," 1994 October (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Jane Austen Society of North America, "Contesting Language in Pride and Prejudice, 1994 November (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - The Houston Seminar, 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Biblion: The Bulletin of the New York Public Library publication, correspondence, 1994-2000 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Leave, "Development of Christmas," 1995 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Southeastern American Society for 18th Century Studies, conference, "Getting Into Print," 1995 February (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Bucknell University, Robbins Lecture, "The Very Dickens: Oliver's Twisted History," 1995 November (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - University of Pennsylvania, lecture on getting published, 1995 November (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Center for Women's Studies, interviews, 1995 December (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Research grant proposal, circa 1995 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston NEH Self-Study Grant Proposal, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Domestic Partner Benefits, 1995-2000 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Retirement party, Sally Hubbard, 1996 January 18 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Friends of Fondren Library, authors reception remarks, 1996 January 31 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - ESFA lecture, "Dickens Invents Himself as Author: Plagiarism as a Capitalist Plot," 1996 March (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - E.D.H. Johnson tribute, 1996 March 9 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - University of California, Irvine, Dean of School of Humanities search, 1996 April (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, NEH report, 1996 July (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Society for the History of Authorship, Reading and Publishing conference, "Rewriting Christmas in Britain, 1843-1848," 1996 July (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dickens Symposium, 1996 September (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Perception, Evolution, and Culture, " 1996 October (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Luminaries: Princeton Faculty Remembered,"Faculty Legends - Edward Dudley Hume Johnson," 1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Rhodes-Marshall scholarships, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - SHARP, book prize correspondence, lists, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Renovations, 1996-1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Texas A (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - TIAE evaluation, 1997 May-June (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - European Comics Seminar materials, 1997 September (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Job application seminar, 1997 October 9 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - South Central Modern Language Association, meeting, "Titular Identity and the Construction of the Author," 1997 October - November (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Univeristy of Houston, English Chair search, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Art historian/chair search, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Terence Hoagwood, Kathryn Ledbetter correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - School of Humanities, Outreach Committee, 1997-2000 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - "Publishable Papers," 1998 January 30 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Committee on Committees, correspondence, reports, 1998 Spring (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 19th Century Geographies Conference, "From House to Square to Street: Narrative Traversals," 1998 March (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Research Society for Victorian Periodicals, 1998 July (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Dickens Project lecture, 1998 August (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Texas Council for the Humanities, Outstanding Teaching the Humanities award to Mrs. Naomi Fanettm, Klein Forest High School, 1998 September (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Museum of Fine Arts Houston, "Evenings for Educators," 1998 October 19 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - SAMLA Convention, 1998 November (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Curriculum, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Faculty Council, spousal hires, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Sarofim pegagogy seminar correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Scholarships and Awards Committee, applications, correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Victorian Studies Review, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Center for Study of Cultures, correspondence, reports, announcements, grants, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - The Letters of Charles Dickens, Pilgrim edition, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Alumni College, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Commencement, correspondence, memos, Marshalls information, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Scottish Centre for the Book, "Dickens as Serial Author: A Case of Multiple Identities, " 1999 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - 'The History of Sex," History Channel, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Houston Seminar, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Museum of Fine Arts Houston, book club, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Scholar's Forum Lecture Series, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Outreach, correspondence, reports, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The South Central Modern Language Association (SCMLA), 1999 (Box 6)
  - 18th Century faculty search, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ad-Hoc Health Committee, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Scholarships and awards, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Wagoner Scholarship, applications, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Texas (U.T.) Humanities Regional Center, proposal information, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - AEB Review, 2000 March (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Houston Seminar, 2000 Spring (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Marshall's notebook, commencement, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Council of Editors of Learned Jounrals (CELJ) Special Issue competition, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 13)